

CONTACT



federico.martin.medina11@gmail.com

https://fede3500.github.io/portfolio

Santander, Spain

in www.linkedin.com/in/federico-m-medina

SOFT SKILLS

- Design systems, UI trends & best practices.
- Design thinking.
- User research & testing.
- Communication.
- New technology domains.
- Knowledge in frontend development cycles.
- Problem solving.
- Proactive.
- Interpersonal skills.

CODING SKILLS

- Javascript
- · React is
- Node is
- Typescript
- Html5 | Css3 | Boostrap5
- JQuery
- Sass
- SQL

LANGUAGES

• Spanish: Native

• Italian: Advanced

• English: Advanced

SOFTWARES

- Trello
- AI tools
- Git
- GitHub
- Jira
- Wordpress
- Zendesk
- Azure
- Google W

DESIGN

- Figma
- Canva
- AdobeXD
- FigJam
- Whimsical

FEDERICO MEDINA

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am passionate about programming and IT, particularly mobile apps and web design where user experience and graphics are the priority. I believe that programming has a significant impact on our lives, and can be used to revolutionize business. I am highly motivated to keep learning and contributing to projects that improve people's lives and transform the business world.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Information Technology Specialist (Remote)

Yondbee Social Effects

Madrid, Spain | Jun 2023 - Currently

- Installation, configuration and updating of programs and operating systems on employee computers.
- Management of networks and VPN connections to guarantee secure access to remote systems.
- Deployment of mobile MDM certificates on devices and monitoring of compliance with security policies.
- Managing Google Workspace, Azure Active Directory and other services.
- Creation and administration of scripts to automate processes and tasks.

Web Developer Specialist & Consultant (Remote)

"Publicate" Advertising & Web services

Buenos aires, Argentina | Dec 2022 - May 2023

- Programming languages used | Sass | HTML5 |
 CSS3 | Bootstrap5 | JavaScript | Wordpress |
 Jquery | ReactJs.
- Tools used GitHub & Git.
- Managing the workflow of the software.
- Maintenance and optimize the website in terms of the user interface.
- Implementation of seo practices on the page.

Customer Experience & IT (Remote)

"Reby" Urban Mobility service

Barcelona, Spain | Feb 2022 - Dec 2022

- Managing a huge amount of conversations with our customers through chat, email and phone.
- Ticket system software CRM "Kustomer Application" (Chats, Phone Calls, Complaints).
- Managing API (Insomnia)
- Being attentive to customer enquiries, feedback and complaints.

Content Marketing & Digital

"Commune of Rio Ceballos"

Cordoba, Argentina | Oct 2020 - Jun 2021

- Content creation and writing.
- Creation of marketing campaigns.
- Planning and executing engaging content on social media.
- Establishing KPIs, control analytics and metrics tools.

Office Assistant

"Claube SRI Cecci" - Hardware Store

Cordoba, Argentina | Jun 2019 - Aug 2020

- Writing and distribute email, correspondence notes, letters, faxes and forms.
- Developing and maintaining a filing system.
- Updating and maintaining office procedures and policies.
- Tools used (Excel, Word, OneDrive, Outlook).

EDUCATION

"VIA"- University Campus Horsens

Denmark | Aug 2022 - Feb2023

Completed 1st Semester of Degree in Software Technology Engineering.

"CEICOS" - Centro de Estudios & Comunicacion Social

Cordoba, Argentina | Jan 2016 - Dec 2018

Diploma: Administration and Communications in Human Resources & Bussines.

BOOTCAMPS

ONE - "Oracle" Next Education

Specialized in Front-end Developer | Nov 2022 - Jun 2023

- Studied Html5 | Css3 | Javascript | Responsive
 Design | JQuery | Boostrap5 | npm | Sass | Figma.
- Studied TypeScript | React js | Node js.
- Studied github & git.
- Working with various projects and launching new apps and web pages.
- · Studied business agility & agile methodologies.
- · WebAPIs & API REST with Json-Server.
- · CRUD with asynchronous javascript.

Ministerio de Educación GCBA

Specialized in UX/UI Designer | Feb 2023 - Jul 2023

- Studied design software (Figma | AdobeXD | Adobe Photoshop).
- Studied visual design & colors.
- · Studied user research & scenarios.
- Studied information architect.
- Studied wireframing & prototypes.
- Studied responsive layouts.
- Studied tools (OptimalWorkShop | Whimsical | FigJam)

COURSES

"Nuevo Milenio High School"

Pc Operation | Jan 2010 - Jun 2010

- Microsoft office packages (Exel, OneDrive, Outlook, Powerpoint, Word, OneNote).
- Managing specific computer applications for administrative procedures.
- Entering data required to update the database.

"Udemy Academy"

Web Development & Design | Aug 2021 - Dec 2021

- Studied Html | Css | Javascript | Wordpress.
- Studied Boostrap | Jquery | Sass | Figma.
- Studied Responsive Design | Git | Github.

"Ceder Institute" - Argentina

Technical Support | Jul 2015 - Dec 2015

- · Studied troubleshootings.
- Studied customer support & customer service.
- Assessments of situations with critical thinking.
- Diagnose technical problems in technology systems and equipment.

"Creahana Institute"

Digital Marketing and Content Marketing | Jan 2018 - Mar 2019

- Studied SEO and SEM.
- Studied google analytics .
- Social Media Advertising.
- Studied of advertising strategies and positioning.

"Google Institute"

Marketing Fundamentals | Apr 2019 - Aug 2019

- Studied structure and fundamentals of marketing.
- Studied email marketing.
- Studied google analytics.

"University of Alicante"

Web Development | Jan 2021 - Jun 2021

- Studied Html | Css.
- Studied Responsive Design.